Let's visit Malaga, Spain.
You're watching World Travel Guide and
today we will take you to the hometown of
Picasso and one of the oldest cities in
Europe. So stay tuned.
Malaga is a city in Spain, capital of the
Province of Malaga in the Autonomous
Community of Andalusia. With a population
of almost 600,000, it is the second most
populous city in Andalusia after Seville.
In the sixth most populous in Spain, it
lies on the Costa del Sol of the
Mediterranean, about 100 kilometers east
of the Strait of Gibraltar.
Malaga's history spans about 2800
years, making it one of the oldest cities
in Europe and one of the oldest
continuously inhabited cities in the
world. According to most scholars, it was
founded about 770 BC by the Phoenicians.
From the 6th century BC, the city was
under the Hegemony of ancient Carthage.
And from 2:18 BC it was ruled by the
Roman Republic. After the fall of the
Empire and the end of Visigothic rule, it
was under Islamic rule for 800 years. But
in 1487 the crown of Castile gained
control in the midst of the Granada War.
The archaeological remains and monuments
from the Phoenician, Roman, Arabic and
Christian eras make the historic center
of the city an open museum displaying its
history of nearly 3000 years.
Malaga is an important tourist
destination. Known as the capital of the
Costa del Sol, an estimated 6,000,000
tourists visit the city each year.
Tourists usually visit the Old Town or
the beaches. The Malaga Harbor is also the
2nd busiest cruise port of the Iberian
Peninsula. Beyond its 16 sunny beaches,
this Andalusian city on the shores of the
Mediterranean has a fascinating cultural
side. The birth place of Pablo Picasso
has reinvented itself in recent years,
inaugurating museums for all tastes.
If you take the combination of sea and
culture and add a lively atmosphere,
fashionable neighborhoods like Soho,
areas such as the port that have been
transformed to offer a more modern image
and monuments with centuries of history,
the result is an exciting city everyone
would want to discover.
The Alcazaba Palace fortress was built in
the 11th century by king baddies of
Granada. It is perfectly adapted to the
contours of the land and takes maximum
advantage of the elevation of a hill. It
is made-up of two concentric spaces. The
outside part is on the lower level and
the inner part houses the palace.
The Cathedral of the Encarnacion is one
of the town's most important monuments.
It is situated in the historic center of
the town. Work began in the first half of
the 16th century in the Gothic style
ordered by the Catholic monarchs and
continued in the 17th and 18th century.
The South tower and the main facade are
unfinished. It has its own gardens and a
beautiful courtyard.
Standing proudly on the Mount Gibraltar
above the Alcazaba, the Castillo de
Gibral Ferro is another medieval Moorish
fortress. The castle was built in the
10th century on the site of a Phoenician
lighthouse, The Sultan of Granada Yousef.
The first enlarge the fortress in the
early 14th century. Although much of the
fortress has been destroyed, the site
provides A fascinating historical
perspective.
The Malaga Picasso Museum is a must see
attraction for lovers of modern art. This
museum in the Old Town displays an
extensive collection of Malaga's famous
native son. The collection represents the
entire span of Picasso's life and art
career, from his earliest studies to his
revolutionary artistic innovations.
Soho is a central neighborhood which is
an icon of urban art and underground
culture in the city of Malaga. Its most
recognizable feature is probably the
large scale graffiti art covering some of
its buildings. These murals include work
by internationally recognized graffiti
artists. The district is easy to explore
on foot and is very close to Malaga's
main tourist area. Its streets feature
independent local businesses with a
strong sense of identity and several art
and cultural centers.
Malaga can be visited year round, but
based on the ideal climate conditions,
cost of travel and avoiding peak holiday
periods, May and June is the best time to
go. Malaga is blessed with a blissful
Mediterranean climate. The city rarely
gets cold, even in winter it is warm
enough.
We hope you enjoyed this short trip to
Malaga. If you love this video, hit the
like button and subscribe. You should
also check out other beautiful cities on
our channel.